cainer.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Policy

## This is the main privacy policy for www.cainer.com

_Updated: May 25th 2018_

About Cookies | How to Manage Cookies

At Cainer.com we collect different types of information about our users for four main reasons: 

  1. To provide personalised services unique to individual users.
  2. To help us to monitor and improve the services we offer. 
  3. To sell advertising space on the site. This helps us to keep part of our site free for people who visit it. 
  4. If we have permission from the user, or where otherwise allowed by law, to market services to them. 

There may be other privacy policies that apply to certain services we provide. Please read these when you register or subscribe for these services on these sites. 

Please follow any links below for further information. 

  * Our principles
  * How we use your information
  * Registration
  * Updating your personal information
  * Use of Cookies
  * About our advertising
  * Changes to the privacy policy

1 We do our very best to protect your privacy by using security technology appropriately. This means: 

  * we make sure that we have appropriate security measures to protect your information; and 
  * we make sure that when we ask another organisation to provide a service for us, they have appropriate security measures. 

2 We will respect your privacy. You should receive marketing only from us. We will make sure it is clear when you can make these choices, for example, we have boxes you need to tick if you want to receive marketing and you can change your preferences if you no longer want to receive it. However, we may email you occasionally with information or questions about your registration, or your subscription account, for example, with reminders, warnings or copyright requests. 

3\. We will collect and use individual user details only if we have your permission or we have sensible business reasons for doing so, such as collecting enough information to manage subscriptions and deliver personalised forecasts. 

4 We will be clear in our dealings with you as to what information about you we will collect and how we will use it. 

5 We will use personal information only for the purposes for which it was originally collected and when no longer required we will make sure we delete it securely. 

6 If we or our service providers transfer any information out of the European Economic Area (EEA), it will only be done with the relevant protection (stated under UK law) being in place. 

###  What information do we collect? 

We collect information on you: 

  * when you register, make a purchase or become a member of our 5 Star service. 
  * when you use the website 
  * through cookies 
  * through UserAgent strings, including IP address, Operating system version and browser details 

Certain services that we provide may involve us collecting extra information (5 Star membership, for example), such as where you are, so the service can be provided as designed. This may also apply to certain apps that you download, or which we provide. 

### Registration

The minimum information we need to register you is your name, email address and a password. We may ask you more questions for different services. 

We may also ask some other questions during registration for certain services (for example, date and place of birth). This allows us to personalise services for you. 

After you have registered, and with your permission, we may send you emails we think may interest you. Newsletters may be personalised based on your purchases and date of birth. If you subscribe to our 5 Star services we will send you emails when any new forecasts are ready or emails about updates to your subscription services. 

###  Updating your personal information 

If you are registered with our 5 Star Service, we offer a 'My Account' page, where you can manage your personal information at any time, and change your marketing preferences. You can get to this page from most pages on the 5 Star site - simply click on the 'My Account' link at the top of the screen when you are signed in. 

###  Who we share data with 

We will not share your personal information with others for marketing purposes unless you have specifically given us your permission. If we have your permission, we will share your information only with other organisations we have chosen carefully. 

We may make other organisations' services available, through our sites, although we are not necessarily operating these sites. We process any information which we collect when you access a service provided by another organisation under this privacy policy. Information these other organisations collect is governed by their own privacy policies. 

We can access and release personal information to keep to relevant laws and government requests, to operate our systems properly and to protect both us and our users. 

Any other organisations who access your information in the course of providing services on our behalf will be governed by strict contractual restrictions to make sure that they protect your information and keep to data-protection and privacy laws which apply. We may also independently audit these service providers to make sure that they meet our standards. We may use service providers to help us run these sites (or services available on the sites), some of whom may be based outside the EEA. 

Some of our webpages use plug-ins from other organisations (such as the 'Facebook Like' function). These other organisations may use information about your visit to our websites on their pages. If you browse these pages while still also logged in to your account with us, information they collect may be connected to your account on their site. For more information on how these organisations use information, please read their privacy policies. 

Please see our pages about cookies: About Cookies | How to Manage Cookies

We use Google Analytics on our sites for anonymous reporting of site usage and for advertising on the site. If you would like to opt-out of Google Analytics monitoring your behaviour on our sites please use this link (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>) 

As you browse our sites, some of the cookies we place on your computer will be advertising cookies, so we can understand what sort of pages you are interested in We can then display advertising on your browser that is based on these perceived interests. For instance if you have been reading a lot of food and drink articles, you may be shown more adverts for food and drink. 

This allows us and some of our advertising partners to show you ads based on your browsing patterns and interactions with a site away from our sites. For example, if you have visited the website of an online clothes shop, you may start seeing ads from that same shopping site displaying special offers or showing you the products that you were browsing. This allows companies to advertise to you if you leave their website without making a purchase. 

Advertising on mobile devices may require the collection and sharing of the unique device ID with companies who purchase advertising space on the mobile application. 

Email: dataprotection@cainer.com 

Mailing Address:   
Reality Marketing Ltd.  
PO Box 954  
Bromley  
Kent  
BR1 9HS  

If you would like access to or a copy of the personal information we hold about you, to request a correction, or have any questions about how we may use it or to make a complaint, please contact the Data Protection Manager at the address shown above. Or, email dataprotection@cainer.com Complaints will be dealt with by the Data Protection Manager, and will be responded to within 30 days at the latest. 

If you are not satisfied with the way your complaint was handled, you may be able to refer your complaint to your local data protection regulator. For example, in the United Kingdom this is the Information Commissioner's Office, and in Australia is the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner. 

Should we elect to change our privacy policy we will post the changes here. Where the changes are significant, we may also choose to email all our registered users with the new details. Where required by law, will we obtain your consent to make these changes.
